# 重要宴会都上过这道菜 很精品
This is a banquet dish, a delicate dish
# 这也是我上学的时候做的一道菜
It is also a dish I made when I was in school
# 传统菜 酸辣瓜条
It’s a traditional dish Spicy and Sour Cucumber
# 今天主要使用的
Today we are using
# 黄瓜 葱丝 姜丝 辣椒丝
Cucumber, Julienne Spring Onion, Julienne Ginger, Julienne Dried Chilies
# 我提前准备好了
I’ve prepared them in advance
# 咱们先把黄瓜处理一下
Let’s first cut the cucumber
# 给大家讲一小窍门
I’ll share some tricks
# 把这个头这儿去完以后
Once you cut off the end
# 咱们手指头这个是变不了的
The length of your finger doesn’t change
# 卡在这儿 一切
So you could measure the length of cucumber strips with your finger
# 这样瓜条到什么时候它都是一边长
To keep them the same size
# 合理的一个大约在五公分
About 5cm
# 黄瓜心咱们给它去掉
Let’s remove the seeds
# 为什么呢 因为黄瓜心它容易出汤
Why? To remove the extra moisture
# 切完了要求它都得一边长
Make sure to keep them the same length
# 出来摆盘比较好看
So they look pretty
# 这个黄瓜条切完了 咱们杀上盐
Once we finish cutting the cucumber, sprinkle some salt on it
# 先出一下水 别怕盐多
Let the moisture come out. Don’t be afraid there’s too much salt
# 稍稍多一点没事
It’s okay to go a little heavy on salt
# 待会咸味一出汤以后就带走了
It will be gone with the moisture
# 咱们把黄瓜先搁一边 腌着备用
Let’s put the cucumber aside, let it sit
# 开始操作了
And start making the sauce
# 最主要的就是辣椒丝 葱丝 姜丝
Mainly Julienne Chili, Spring Onion and Julienne Ginger
# 这都是我提前准备好的
I’ve prepared them in advance
# 这个量还挺大的
This is a big portion
# 这个汁儿咱们可以多炒一点
You can make it in advance
# 您分两次或者三次吃都可以
And use it whenever it’s needed
# 下面咱们调汁 点火
Let’s start! Turn on the stove
# 锅烧热了 咱们记住一定是放香油
Warm the wok. Make sure to use sesame oil
# 香油香啊
It’s aromatic
# 过去做凉菜炒汁的时候
We’ve always used sesame oil
# 一般使香油使的比较多
When making sauce for cold dished
# 这个菜香油必须得加热
Sesame oil must be heated for this dish
# 不加热它的香度太大
Otherwise it will be overly aromatic
# 然后通过加热把一些浓度释放出来
So by heating it, we let the aroma evaporate for a bit
# 先煸姜 先下姜
Put the Julienne ginger first
# 姜丝 葱丝
Julienne ginger and Julienne spring onion
# 这个菜的关键就是用香油煸
The key for this dish is to fry with sesame oil
# 辣椒丝 把它煸出香味来
Add Julienne dried chili and fry until aromatic
# 咱们注意 这个辣椒别给它炒糊了
Be careful to not burn the chili
# 油温别太高 搁进去以后一下糊了
Don’t bring the temperature too high, otherwise it will burn
# 它影响后边的口感
It affects the taste
# 大爷你看没有香油味都没了
Da Ye, there’s no overt sesame oil aroma now
# 全是辣椒和葱姜丝的味
It’s full of the aroma of chili, spring onion and ginger
# 葱姜丝的香味出来了
The aroma of ginger and spring onion has been released
# 咱们下边 米醋
Now, add rice vinegar
# 北京的米醋 北京米醋有名
Beijing rice vinegar, it’s popular
# 然后咱们光是米醋的味道不够
Just rice vinegar is not enough
# 咱们再加点白醋
Let’s also add some white vinegar
# 加白醋的味道立马就窜出来了
The aroma is out once you add white vinegar
# 你这糖也不少加啊
That’s quite a lot of sugar too
# 有三百克差不多吧
About 300g
# 就因为加了糖以后
Sugar gives
# 它这汁粘稠了而且有亮度
Consistency and brightness
# 咱们这样太浓了这汁 咱再加点水
Now it’s too thick, let’s add some water
# 这能泡好多黄瓜啊
The sauce can be used for lots of cucumbers
# 咱们这个汁一次调好了以后
Once the sauce is made
# 可以放在冰箱里 它也不坏
It can be kept in the fridge. It doesn’t go bad
# 加点盐
Add some salt
# 来咱们点一点酱油
And soy sauce
# 实际上这是凉菜一个特殊的味道
This dish actually has a special taste
# 一个味儿型
A taste type
# 适合自己的才是好的味道
Whatever taste you like is the best
# 咱们这边差不多了 晾凉
It’s done. Let’s remove it from the wok and let it cool
# 咱们熬汁的时候速度要快
We need to move quickly when we make the sauce
# 锅一开咱们就得给它盛出来
Remove it from the pot as soon as it boils
# 要不然醋挥发的就跑了
Otherwise, the vinegar will get evaporated
# 然后再搁冰箱里边腌制（镇凉）
Put the sauce in the fridge
# 你看现在腌了多长时间了
Check how long it’s been (for the cucumber)
# 有个半个小时
It’s been half an hour
# 刚开始腌的时候是出汤
The moisture came out at first
# 然后一刻钟时候我尝了是皮的
I tasted it at after 15 minutes, it’s soft
# 现在你看时间到了是脆的
Now it’s crunchy
# 您看着里面的水
Look at the liquid that came out
# 咱把它给倒出去 篦出去
Discard it
# 所以说它必须得腌够了时间
You must give it enough time
# 把它澄干净
Drain it all out
# 您看咱们这个汁也凉了 越凉越粘稠
The sauce has cooled down, and become thick
# 咱们把这个汁倒进去
Pour the sauce in the cucumber
# 大爷你这要搁一宿
Da Ye, if you let it marinate overnight
# 明天早上再吃才 那爽
And eat it tomorrow. It will be tastier.
# 咱们把这拌一下
Let’s mix it
# 明天早上一吃 脆爽脆爽的
Eat it tomorrow, it will be tasty and crunchy
# 咱们这个再腌俩小时 俩小时以后 好
Let’s have it marinate for two more hours. After two hours
# 放冰箱里头镇一下
Chill it in the fridge
# 师伯咱么这个腌好了
It’s done Shi Bo
# 您看这个黄瓜条
Look at the cucumber
# 皮儿朝上 而且瓜条宽窄长短都一样了
Face the skin-side up. All the strips have the same size
# 这样摆出来就整齐好看
So that it looks nice and neat
# 行了差不多了
Almost done
# 差不多了 然后咱们把这个料
Let’s add the condiments on top
# 把料搁在上边 点缀
For decoration
# 你看这没有过多的去修饰 简简单单
No extra decorations keep it simple
# 四十年前的味道 一点都没走味儿
Tastes like how it was 40 years ago, nothing has changed
# 为什么老说这小菜很重要
Why do we always say that starters are important
# 到一酒店吃饭 进门的菜是什么菜
Because, what are the first dishes you see when dining?
# 不是热菜 是凉菜
Not mains but appetizers
# 重要宴会其实都上过这道菜 很精品
This dish has been presented on important banquets, it’s very delicate
# 这个汁咱们还可以做
We can also use the sauce in making
# 黄瓜皮 黄瓜卷 萝卜皮
Cucumber skin, shaved cucumber, radish skin
# 油吃黄瓜 珊瑚白菜
Cucumber marinated in oil, Coral Napa Cabbage
# 基本上和这个口味上差不多
Flavours are all similar
# 今天让我们来康康宝藏男孩郑秀生的日常
Today, let’s see Treasure Boy Zhe Xiusheng’s (Da Ye) daily life
# 他喜欢唱歌
He likes singing
# 随时来两首小曲
He sings as he pleases
# 他用实力卖萌
He acts cute
# 实力模仿魏刚强
Imitate Wei Gangqiang (Er Bai’s apprentice)
# 大爷
Da Ye
# 走了
Leaving
# 他博学多才
He is of great learning and great ability
# 你得有一个正能量
You must hold a positive attitude
# 要给这些孩子们
You must be able to tell the descendants
# 讲出些门门道道来
the theories and methodology
# 家有大厨 就是幸福
Happy life with a chef at home
# 这样的大爷你爱了吗
Do you like Da Ye like this?
# 今天我们来盘点一下颜值担当孙立新
Let’s now talk about handsome Sun Lixin (Er Bai)
# 他沉迷诗歌
He loves poetry
# 爹娘深深的系着我的爱恋
(Reading a poem)
# 期待着如期般的守望
# 他金句频频
He tells verse
# 演绎着人间的温暖
Interpreting the warmth of the world
# 靠我们厨师去温暖这个世界
Let us, chefs to warm the world
# 他多才多艺
He is versatile
# 我还学过织毛衣呢
I’ve learned knitting
# 你以为呢
What do you think?
# 无情铁手剥花生
Peeling peanuts
# 最后我们康康别人眼中的他
Finally, let’s see other people’s perspectives of him
# 孙老师啊是我们烹饪界的美男子
Sun is the handsome man in culinary industry
# 烹饪界的中医大夫
The Chinese doctor in culinary industry
# 烹饪界的理论家和哲学家
The theorist and philosopher in culinary industry
# 这样的二伯您喜欢吗
Do you like Er Bai like this?